Guide to the Andrei Voznesenskii Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 1.2: Leaves
    - Subsubseries 1.2.1: Poems
      - "Novye stikhi" (Collection of poems)01.10.2001, An annotated photocopy of a clipping from the newspaper "Moskovskii komsomolets", 1 page, damaged. (Box 9, Folder 49)
        Viktor Vasnetsov; Kleopatra; Anri-Mari Raimon de Tuluz-Lotrek Monfa; Claudius Ptolemaeus [Ptolemy].
      - "O Gruziia, ty - panorama..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - "Obuchenie vinopitiiu"; "P.S."n.d., Two galley copies [?] with handwritten corrections, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Ochisti, sneg"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        P. [Pavel ?] Stepanov.
      - "Odnazhdy slon uvleksia aerobikoi..."n.d., Handwritten rough drafts, 5 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "Oksana-2001"n.d., An annotated typescript, 2 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 4)
        Renata Litvinova.
      - "Osen' v Sigulde"n.d., An annotated galley copy [?], incomplete (the beginning is missing), 1 page, severely damaged. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - "Osennii para-sailing"n.d., A galley copy, 3 pages. (Box 10, Folder 6)
        Immanuel Kant; Friedrich Schelling.
      - "Ostav' pechal'! Prokatis' na rolikakh..."n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page, slightly damaged, with other handwritten notes and a typewritten fragment [?] of a poem "Son" on the other side. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Otkrytie chernogo kvadrata"n.d., An annotated typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 8)
        Kazimir Malevich; Vasilii [Vasily] Chekrygin; Karl-Hajns SHtokgauzen; Andrei Chikatilo.
      - "Otshumevshie shkoly..."n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 9)
        VIktor Shklovskii.
      - "P.S." [1 of 2]n.d., An annotated typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - "P.S." [2 of 2]n.d., A galley copy with a correction, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 11)
        A poem (another poem with the same title).
      - "Palindrom"n.d., A typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - "Pamiati B.P."n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 13)
        Boris Pasternak [?].
      - "Pamiati G.Gorina"n.d., A galley copy with a minor correction, 1 page, and a handwritten rough draft, 1 page, severely damaged. (Box 10, Folder 14)
        Grigorii Gorin.
      - "Pamiatnik-001"n.d., An annotated photocopy of a typescript, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 15)
        Gavrila [Gavriil] Derzhavin; Anakreon.
      - "Para-shut"n.d., A galley copy, 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 16)
        Andrei Makarevich; Vladimir Tatlin; Sergei Esenin; Edward [?] Olby.
      - "Parashiut"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - "Parlamenter"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - "Pershit v gorle zapiataia..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - "Pervyi (v zhizni) sneg"n.d., An annotated photocopy of a typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - "Pesnia spaseniia" and other draftsn.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 21)
        Incl. poems, among others: "Pesnia spaseniia".
      - "Piat' s pliusom"2002 [n.d.], An annotated typewritten draft, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - "Pis'ma iz zheltogo doma" (A collection of poems)2002 [n.d.], A typescript, 127 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 23)
        Incl. poems and prosaic works, among others: "Sad", "Zheltyi dom", "Kupanie v rose", "Pomilui, Gospodi...", "Ballada o Mo", "Platite zhenshchine", "More", "Shalanda zhelanii", "Plach' po Bulatu, pribludshaia devochka...", "Primi, Gospod', poeta ulits...", "Khram", "Ispoved' mordovskoi madonny", "Ulet", "Lesnoi regtaim", "Para-shut", "Za chto moi vskhody rastoptany...", "Ne pytaite lampoi paial'noiu...", "Klavishami Berlioza...", "Volshebnoe steklo", "Casino 'Rossiia' ", "Spasite cheremukhu", "Arenda", "Ia ne veriu v koshmar izotermy...", "Ne brosaite musor u moei kalitki!..", "Ochisti, sneg", "Letal'nyi leitenant", "Dacha", "Veteran", "Uedem v NN", "Maslenitsa", "V khrame", "Minchanka", ""Disput", "Provintsial'nyi romans", "Motyl'kovyi tvoi vozrast...", "Edva prosypaius' vo mrake...", ""Nirvana", "Ave Rave", "Parlamenter", "Chucheloveche", "Russkie siamochki", "Aktrisa", "Ekran", "Osennii para-sailing", "Idu po nebu na parashiute...", "Parashiut", "Fialki - tvoi filialy...", "Vechnyi russkii", "Podrazhanie shotlandtsam", "Proshchai, Allen...", "Istoriia", "Domoi!", "Sladkim rotikom ot khalvy...", "P.S.", "Kara Karfagena", "Belye figury", "Mesiats", "U Medveditsy techka...", "Ne dai nam, Gospodi, sorvat'sia!..", "Trans", "Russkaia playmate", "Drugu", "Smert' Klavdiia", "Kaballisticheskaia ekspertiza", "Figury na beregu", "Revet sudilishcha orda...", "Pamiati B.P.", "Bezdna", "Temnaia figura", "Kompra", "Virtual'naia klaviatura".
        Nikolai Gogol'; Dzhokhar Dudaev; Mikhail Kutuzov; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart; Bulat Okudzhava; [Antonio ?] Gaudi; Alla Pugacheva; Madonna; Andzei [Andjei] Vaida; Aleksandr Blok; Antonio Vivaldi; Sergei Kurekhin [Kuryokhin]; Andrei Makarevich; Vladimir Tatlin; Sergei Esenin; Hector Berlioz; Antonio Stradivari; Afanasii Fet [Shenshin]; Kazimir Malevich; Aleksandr Pushkin; Iosif Stalin; Grigorii Zinoviev; Aleksei Rykov; Semen Budennyi; Eduard Radzinskii; Petr Chaikovskii; Fedor Dostoevskii; Lev Tolstoi; Ermak; Sviatoslav Belza; Oleg Kulik; Garik Sukachev; Pierre Cardin; Pablo Picasso; Nikita Khrushchev; Allen Ginsberg; Inna Churikova; Napoleon Bonaparte; Liubov' Orlova; Vladimir Lenin; Nils Bor [Bohr]; Franz Shubert; Velimir Khlebnikov; Nina Iskrenko; Aleksandr Iakovlev; Leonardo da Vinci; Feliks Iusupov; Boris Pasternak; Aleksei Musin-Pushkin; Pablo de Sarasate; P. [Pavel ?] Stepanov; Isaak Levitan; Bill Clinton; Boris Yeltsin; Paul McCartney; Grigorii Iavlinskii; Irina Khakamada; [Ivan ?] Bilibin; Irina Khalip; Mikhail Gorbachev; Edward [?] Olby; Hillary Clinton; Karl Marx; Friedrich Engels; Nikolai II; Raffaello Sanzio [Raphael]; Maurice Ravel; Ilya Repin; George Bush; Mikhail Lermontov; Jacque Chirac; Yehudi [Yegudi] Menukhin [Menuhin]; Bob Dylan; Salvador Dali; Rodriges [Rodrigez] de Silva Velaskes [Velasquez]; Riurik; Nikolai Rerikh; Vanessa Redgrave; Vera Chashkina; Maris Liepa; Immanuel Kant; Friedrich Schelling; Robert Falk; Senator Cato; Barbra Streisand; Ezra Pound; Hermann Hesse; Marilyn Monroe; Claudio Ptolomei [?]; Nicolaus Copernicus [Mikolai Kopernik]; Sigmund Freud; Mikhail Tariverdiev; Iulian [Julian] [?] Tuvim; Ivan Boduen de Kurtene [Jan Ignacy Baudouin de Courtenay]; Franz Kafka; Slava Iaponchik; Alimzhan Tokhtakhunov [Taivanchik]; Klaudia Shiffer; Francesco Petrarca; Laura; Adolf Hitler; Eva Brown; Marat Helman; Naomi Campbell; Catherine the Great [Ekaterina II]; Pierre Auguste Renuar; Fanni Kaplan; Filip Kirkorov; Vladimir Sorokin; Socrates; Girolamo Savonarola; Andrei Siniavskii; Martin Luther; Diana, Princess of Wales; Plotin; Kserks; Marcel Dushamp; Liudmila Zykina; John Lennon; Sergei Iurskii; Gustav Eiffel; Sergei Chekhonin; Vladimir Gilyarovskii [Gilyarovsky]; Kuz'ma Minin; Friedrich Nietzsche; Frederick Chopin; Vincent Van Gogh; Iurii Bashmet; Alessandro Kaliostro; Salmon Rushdi [Rushdie]; Boris Slutskii; Mikelandgelo [Michelangelo] Buonarroti; Moris Bezhar [Bejar]; Plinii; Iurii Nagibin; Arthur Shopengauer; Rudyard Kipling; Lawrence Ferlinghetti; Elvis Presley; Alfred Schnittke; Vasilii [Vasily] Vereshchagin; Garry Kasparov; Caligula; Vasilii Aksenov; Mikhail Pozdniaev; Mikhail Chigorin; Makhmud [Makhmut] Esambaev; Vladimir Nabokov; Attila; Francois-Andre; Danican Philidor [?]; Anna Akhmatova; Elton John; Sting; Mata Hari; Vladimir Maiakovskii; Gata Kamskii; Klaudia Shiffer; Bobby Fischer; Ivan the Terrible; David Copperfield; Sviatoslav Richter; Vasilii Kandinskii; Auguste Roden; Henrih Neigauz; Nina Dorliak; Father Vedernikov; Titian [Tiziano Vecellio]; Robert Falk; Marc Shagall [Chagall].
      - "Plach' po Bulatu, pribludshaia devochka..."n.d., A galley copy with a minor correction, 1 page, an annotated galley copy, 1 page, damaged, and a handwritten rough draft, 1page, severely damaged, with a handwritten note on the other side. (Box 10, Folder 24)
        Incl. a poem and a handwritten note from A.Voznesenskii to militia officers.
      - "Plachet mladenets golen'kii..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - "Plastinka"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page, and an annotated galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - "Platite zhenshchine"n.d., A galley copy, 2 pages, and an annotated galley copy, 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 27)
        Plotin; Kserks.
      - "Pochemu mne snitsia Sukhareva vsadnitsa?.."n.d., Two handwritten rough drafts, 2 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - "Podrazhanie shotlandtsam" ("Ia obozhaiu myshonka za to, chto on velikan...")n.d., An annotated galley copy, 1 page, two handwritten rough drafts on The University of Edinburgh's stationery, 2 pages, slightly damaged, and other drafts / notes, 2 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 29)
        A poem and miscellaneous notes.
        Mikelandgelo [Michelangelo] Buonarroti; Moris Bezhar.
      - "Poetarkh"n.d., A typescript (probably incomplete) with numerous handwritten notes / drafts including a rough draft of the poem "Ty menia ne ostavliai...", 2 pages, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 30)
        Plutarch; Boris Pasternak; Gavrila [Gavriil] Derzhavin; Aleksandr Pushkin.
      - "Poka artachimsia i mechemsia..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - "Pomilui, Gospodi..." ("Sergiev Posad")02.12.1997 - [03.14.1997], An annotated galley copy, 2 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 32)
        Andrei Siniavskii [Abram Terts]; Maria Rozanova [Siniavskaia]; Martin Luther.
      - "Pop-pevets" ("Estradnyi pevets", "My, vampiry...")n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 33)
        Aleksandr Vampilov.
      - "Pora paraseilinga"n.d., A galley copy [?] with a minor handwritten addition, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - "Portret Plisetskoi" ("Maiia")n.d., An annotated typescript, 7 pages, the last one is severely damaged, with several handwritten notes. Incl. also a handwritten title of the text on a separate page. (Box 10, Folder 35)
        Maiia Plisetskaia; Marina Tsvetaeva; Anri [Henri] de Toulouse-Lautrec; Amedeo Modigliani; Vladimir Maiakovskii; Marc Shagall [Chagall]; Henry Moor; Alexander [Aleksandr] Tyshler.
      - "Poslanie V.Aksenovu [?]..."n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page ("The Jumeirah Beach Hotel" stationery), slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 36)
        Vasilii Aksenov [?].
      - "Poslednie sem' slov Khrista"n.d., A typescript with handwritten notes on the 1st page, 11 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 37)
        Franz Josef Haydn; Christian Dior; Dante Alighieri; Sergei Esenin; Saddam Hussein.
      - "Poslednii raz - samyi sladostnyi..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - "Posviashchenie"n.d., An annotated typescript, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 39)
      - "Primi, Gospod', poeta ulits..."n.d., A galley copy, 1 page, and an annotated galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 40)
      - "Proraby dukha"n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 2 pages, with a rough draft of a poem "Khudozhnik" (a fragment) on the other side of the 1st page and with a rough draft of a poem "Tri sinikh" (a fragment) on the other side of the 2d page. Slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 41)
        Velimir Khlebnikov; Carlo Rossi; Aleksandr [Alexander] Herzen; Semen Geichenko; Boiarynia [Lady] Morozova [?].
      - "Proshchai, Allen..." ("Ne vyderzhivaet pechen'...")n.d., An annotated galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 42)
        Allen Ginsberg; Iosif Stalin; Bob Dylan.
      - "Prosnulsia ia - mgla produtaia..."n.d., A typescript, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 43)
      - "Provintsial'nyi romans"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 44)
        Vincent Van Gogh.
      - "Pushtorg"n.d., An annotated typescript, 1 A3 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 45)
        Aleksandr Pushkin; Nikolai Gogol'; Anna Akhmatova; Yasser Arafat.
      - "Retsepty"n.d., A typescript with a handwritten correction, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 46)
        Nicolo [?] Amati.
      - "Revet sudilishcha orda..."n.d., A galley copy, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 47)
        Vasilii [Vasily] Vereshchagin.
      - "Rossiia voskrese. Sonet dliashchegosia molitvosloviia"n.d., An annotated typescript, 15 pages, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 48)
        Kris Kelmi; Bob Dylan; Lekh [Lech] Valensa; Blaise Pascal; Boris Yeltsin; Kserks; Anne Veski; Urmas Ott; Maiia Plisetskaia; Viktor Astafiev; Pierre Boulez; Elvis Presley; Wolf Messing; Homer.
      - "Russkaia pesenka iz spektaklia"n.d., A typescript, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 49)
      - "Russkaia playmate" ("Zhrite, russkie pel'meni, soplemennikov..."), "Smert' rozy", "Ekran"n.d., One page with typewritten drafts of three poems with numerous handwritten additions / corrections, damaged, and two annotated galley copies of the poems "Russkaia playmate" and "Ekran", 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 50)
        Poems "Russkaia playmate" ("Zhrite, russkie pel'meni, soplemennikov..."), "Smert' rozy", and "Ekran".
        Salvador Dali; Alessandro Kaliostro.
      - "Russkie siamochki"n.d., A galley copy with a correction, 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 51)
        Nefertiti.
      - "Russkii noveishina"n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page, damaged. (Box 10, Folder 52)
      - "Sad"n.d., A galley copy, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 53)
      - "Se chelovek"n.d., An annotated typescript, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 54)
        Che Guevara; Sergei Esenin; Vincent Van Gogh; Saddam Hussein.
      - "Shalanda zhelanii"1993 [?]; n.d., Two annotated galley copies, 2 pages total, a handwritten rough draft, 1 page, slightly damaged, and a handwritten rough draft on the page of the catalogue "Andrei Voznesenskii. Videomy. Gosudarstvennyi muzei izobrazitel'nykh iskusstv imeni A.S.Pushkina. Moskva, 1993" (18 pages, slightly damaged; the staples were removed by an archivist, 07.25.2005). (Box 10, Folder 55)
        Marcel Dushamp; Aleksandr Pushkin; Boris Pasternak; Iurii Tynianov; Velimir Khlebnikov; Robert Rauschenberg; Shozo Shimamoto [?]; Ray Johnson; Father Pavel Florenskii; Nikolai Gumilev; Guillaume Apollinaire; Aleksandr Men'; Allen Ginsberg; Oscar Wilde [Wylde]; Marc Shagall [Chagall]; Salvador Dali; Sviatoslav Richter; Genrikh Sapgir; Leonard Bernstein; Anna Akhmatova; Vladimir Nabokov; Vladimir Maiakovskii; Ivan Barkov; Madonna; Marcel Proust; Isadora Duncan; Denis Fonvizin; Aleksandr [Alexander] Tairov; Sergei Prokofiev; Nikita Khrushchev; Igor' Severianin; Iosif Stalin; Osip Mandel'shtam; Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis; Nikolai Zabolotskii; Dante Alighieri; James Rosenquist; Maiia Plisetskaia; Ieshi Takota [?]; Rodion Shchedrin; Alain Bosquet.; Gosudarstvennyi muzei izobrazitel'nykh iskusstv imeni A.S.Pushkina.
      - "Shar ada" (Collection of works)12.05-11.2001, An annotated proof, 4 A3 pages, some are damaged. (Box 10, Folder 56)
        Incl. poems "Beremennye slova", "Son", "Killerka, ili Dymok nad pl. Maiakovskogo", "Byl chelovekom-ekskrementom...", "Byt' zhenshchinoi", "Mar'iana", "Doch' khudozhnika", "Sharp-2. Ekho poemy", "Predchuvstvie Novogo 2000 goda", "...Zhit', liubit' - i bol'she nikogda..." [?], and an essay "Dekabr' - debarkader".
        Vladimir Maiakovskii; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart; Anton Chekhov [Tchekhov]; Igor' Stravinskii; Gustav Mahler; Nikolai Miaskovskii; Christian Dior; Pierre Cardin; Vivien Lee; Vladimir Zhirinovskii; Valeriia Novodvorskaia; Louis Aragon; Benedict de Spinoza; Elza Triole; Arthur Rimbaud [Arthur Rembo]; Francois Rabelais; Fidel Castro; Robert De Niro; Boris Nemtsov [?]; Lada Dens; Iurii Liubimov [?]; Oleg Men'shikov [?]; Vakhtang Kikabidze; Genrikh Sapgir; Dmitrii [Dmitry] Shparo; Mikhail Gorbachev; Mikhail Lermontov; Boris Yeltsin; Anna Pavlova; Lilia Brik.
      - "Shar-pei"n.d., Two annotated typewritten pages with small drawings and a handwritten rough draft on the other side. Slightly damaged. (Box 10, Folder 57)
        Incl. a fragment of a poem.
        Mikhail Lermontov; Igor' Severianin; Wystan Hugh Auden.
      - "Sharp-2. Ekho poemy" and other poemsn.d., Annotated typescripts / handwritten rough drafts, 26 pages total, some with other handwritten drafts / notes, 15 pages of printed illustrations / visual poetry with Voznesenskii's handwritten technical notes on some pages (some leaves are slightly damaged), and a damaged unposted envelope with handwritten notes. (Box 10, Folder 58)
        Incl. poems "Sharp-2. Ekho poemy" (incomplete), "Tri ada", "Khodit po pliazhu rizhskomu musorshchik...", "XXL", "Zolotaia sineva", "Za zvukovym porogom" ("Tabun samoletov vryvaetsia v byt..."), "Vetrenno", "...no Vremia eto shar letiashchii po naklonu...", "Gde vykhod?", and "Dymok nad pl. Maiakovskogo" (the title only). Incl. also a handwritten note from A.Voznesenskii to Aleksei Pavlov on the envelope.
        Aleksei Pavlov; Peter I; Karl Marx; Boris Yeltsin; [Nikolai ?] Feshin; Vladimir Zhirinovskii; Boris Nemtsov [?]; Lada Dens; Iurii Liubimov [?]; Oleg Men'shikov [?]; Vakhtang Kikabidze; Anna Pavlova; Usama Bin Laden; Robert De Niro; Genrikh Sapgir; Dmitrii [Dmitry] Shparo; Lilia Brik; Mikhail Gorbachev; Mikhail Lermontov; Vladimir Maiakovskii.
      - "Shchenok po imeni 'Avos' ' "n.d., A handwritten rough draft, 1 page. (Box 11, Folder 1)
        Pierre Cardin.
      - "Shlo ubiistvo"n.d., An annotated typescript, 3 pages, slightly damaged, and a typescript with handwritten additions, 1 page (the end is missing). (Box 11, Folder 2)
        Nikolai Leskov; John Lennon; Ivan Bunin.
      - "Shuler. Kvintet"n.d., An annotated typescript (a photocopy of a typescript ?), 5 pages, damaged. (Box 11, Folder 3)
        Martin Heidegger; David Copperfield; Martin Heidegger; Diana, Princess of Wales; Dodik Kotkin; Arkhip Kuindzhi; Ekaterina [II ?]; Robert Shuman; Franz Peter Schubert; Kliment [Klement] Voroshilov; Andrei Zhdanov; Mikhail Bulgakov; Charles Dickens; Gavrila [Gavriil] Derzhavin; Kirsan Iliumzhinov; Marc Shagall [Chagall].
      - "Shut"n.d., An annotated galley copy, 3 pages, damaged. (Box 11, Folder 4)
        Andrei Makarevich; Vladimir Tatlin; Sergei Esenin.
      - "Simf-9"n.d., A typescript, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 11, Folder 5)
        Ludvig [Ludwig] van Beethoven.
      - "Skameika - po-russki meiklavka..."n.d., A typescript with a handwritten addition, 1 A3 page, slightly damaged. (Box 11, Folder 6)
        Michelangelo Buonarroti.
      - "Sladkim rotikom ot khalvy..."n.d., A galley copy, 1 page, and a galley copy with a minor handwritten addition, 1 page. Slightly damaged. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - "Smert' Klavdiia"n.d., A galley copy, 2 pages. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - "Snegasnega..."n.d., A handwritten rough draft of a videoma and other notes, 1 page (The University of Edinburgh's stationery), slightly damaged. (Box 11, Folder 9)
        A visual poem and miscellaneous notes.
      - "Sobranie sochinenii. Tom 3. Stikhotvoreniia. Poemy. Rifmy prozy" [1 of 3]1977-1984, A typescript, pages 1-100, some leaves are slightly damaged. (Box 11, Folder 10)
        Incl. poems: "Mat' ", "Vestnitsa", "Dereviannyi zal", "Sestra", "Proportsii", "Vizhu kak son - ty stoish' v polukruge...", "Idu ia rosoi predpokosnoi...", "Rok", "Prosto - nashe shosse i shipovnik...", "Riabina v Parizhe", "Dogadka", "Mysliashchii promyshlennik", "Dukhovnoe vziatochnichestvo", "Akh, letuchaia businka boli...", "Zombi zabven'ia", "V topoliakh", "Redkie krazhi", "Sinii zhurnal", "Nel'zia v tu zhe reku stat' dvazhdy...", "Tikho-tikho. Slyshno tochno...", "Proshlo mnogo li malo...", "Rezinovye", "Rimskii pliazh", "Shtil' ", "Tri skripki", "Lastochki", "Poetarkh", "Monolog veka", "Rech' ", "Pervyi avtobus", "Bezotchetnoe", "Nedopisannaia krasavitsa", "Nevezukha", "Svet druga", "Trubadury i biurgery", "Vystavka 'Moskva-Parizh' ", "Instruktsiia", "Vy chitali? - zadavili Chelentano...", "Sobaka", "Pamiati Vladimira Vysotskogo", "Naverno, ty skoro zabudesh'...", "Ust'e", "Razmolvka", "Ty zhivesh' do kontsa otkrovenno...", "Imena", "Kritiku", "Ia tak schitaiu. A kto ne smyslit...", "Kogda ia slushu vizg vash shkurnyi...", "Monakhinia moria", "Mulatka", "Chernaia bereza", "Belaia", "U kraia polia, v neprogliadnom veke...", "Ballada", "Iablokopad", "Rama", "Dozornyi pered polem Kulikovym", "Saigak", "U moria", "Vodianye", "Vozdushnye luzhi", "Telegramma", "Ni v pastvu ne gozhus', ni v pastukhi...", "Gruzinskie khramy", "Kogda zvoniu iz gorodov dalekikh...", "Iz Meksiki", "Mekhiko-siti", "Prokhodish' ty bez poputchika...", "Akh, perekhod v poloskakh belykh...", "Viion", "Okno", "Pod utro ty pridesh' nazad...", "My vse zabudem, vse s toboi zabudem...", "Ia shel asfal'tom. Seryi den'...", "Vechnoe miaso", "Posviashchenie", "Oda odezhde", "Dezhurnaia aptekarsha", "Koshka", "Liubov' i gore - vne sovetov...", "Dumaite postupkami".
        Antonina Voznesenskaia; Anna Akhmatova; Niccolo Paganini; Pablo Casals; Aleksandr [Alexander] Herzen; Sigmund Freud; Dante Alighieri; Lucas Kranakh; Peter I; Boris Pasternak; Marina Tsvetaeva; Osip Mandel'shtam; Sergei Esenin; Vladimir Maiakovskii; Roden Augustus; Aleksandr Blok; Aleksandr Pushkin; Petr Viazemskii; Velimir Khlebnikov; Francisco [Francesco]Petrarca; Vladimir Vysotskii; Francois Villon; Gavriil [Gavrila] Derzhavin; Demosfen [Demosthenes]; Giacomo Puccini; Archpriest Avvakum; Fedor Abramov; Thomas Stearns Eliot; Leonardo da Vinci; Pablo Picasso; Aleksandr [Aleksandr] Rodchenko; Aristarkh Lentulov; Isadora Duncan; Konstantin Korovin; Ivan Michurin; Adriano Celentano; Djuna Davitashvili; Dmitrii Grigorovich; Bulat Okudzhava; Raimond Pauls; William Shakespeare; Iurii Gagarin; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart; Sviatoslav Richter; Petr Chaikovskii; Gennadii Rozhdestvenskii; Prepodobnyi Sergii Radonezhskii; Vladimir [?] Orlov; Rodion Shchedrin; Kazimir Malevich; Henri Matisse; Paul Gogen; Anton Chekhov [Tchekhov]; Franz Schubert; Valentin Rasputin; Tamerlan [Teymur Lang]; Caligula; Robert Lowell; Karl Marx; Benjamin Britten; Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec; Viacheslav Zaitsev; Lucius Sergius Catilina; Natalia Goncharova [Pushkina].
      - "Sobranie sochinenii. Tom 3. Stikhotvoreniia. Poemy. Rifmy prozy" [2 of 3]1964-1983, A typescript, pages 101-206. (Box 11, Folder 11)